Tell your neighbor bold confession.
This is where we have access
assured.
The Bible says in verse 16, let us then
approach God's throne of grace with
what?
With what?
Confidence.
So that we may receive mercy and find
grace to help us in our time of need.
In that verse, if just go back to that
verse, it is broken in three parts.
Number one, let us then approach God's
throne. In other words, he's saying
there has been an invitation given.
Access, he says, now approach. Why?
There's a high priest positioned.
But then this high priest is a very
interesting high priest. Look at verse
15 of that same chapter.
What kind of a high priest are we
dealing with?
In verse 15, it says this,
for we do not have a high priest who is
unable to do what?
Empathize with our weaknesses.
Hallelujah.
For we do not have a high priest who is
unable to empathize with our weaknesses.
But we have one who has been tempted
in every way
just as we are tempted, yet he did not
do what? Sin. And because he understands
us
and because he knows us and because he
has walked where we have walked, sat
where we sat, slept where we slept, we
have an invitation to enter
into his space.
So tell your neighbor, access has been
assured.
You have been invited. The Bible says
this, God has opened the door for you.
Let me read Revelation chapter 3 verse 7
to 8. The The is open. You can walk
through. The door is open. Your high
priest is on the other side.
He says to the angel of the church in
Philadelphia, write.
These are the words of him who is holy
and true, who holds the key of David.
What he opens
no one can shut.
And what he shuts
no one can
open.
I know your deeds. See, I have placed
before you
an open door
that no one can shut.
God is saying
the door into the throne room is open.
So, number one, the invitation has been
given. The place is a special place. It
is the throne room of God.
It's where God makes decisions.
It's the throne of grace where God
accepts you just the way you are.
Bwana asifiwe.
You don't have to come with a diploma.
You don't have to come with a degree.
You don't need to come with a
certificate. Just come the way you
are. Come to the throne of God boldly.
Confidence. Now, let me read it in the
amplified version one more time. It says
this.
Verse 16.
Romans.
Not Romans. Hebrews.
Chapter 4, verse 16.
In the amplified version.
It says, therefore, let us with
privilege
approach the throne of grace.
Huh? That is the throne of God's
gracious favor. In that place, you're
already favored.
In that place, you're already favored.
So, come in. You're favored.
Don't tiptoe into God's presence.
Tell your neighbor don't tiptoe.
You know, sometimes some of us come into
God's presence to not tiptoe.
Do not tiptoe. Uh-huh. Tukiskia sauti
tunataka hepa.
>> [sighs]
>> The God who is in there already loves
you.
He has already shed his blood and you're
accepted.
And God is saying, "Just walk in. Just
come in.
He's waiting for you."
And it is a place where your needs are
already provided. Look at that verse
again. Therefore, let us with privilege
approach the throne of grace, that is
the throne of God's gracious favor, with
confidence
and without fear so that we may receive
for our failures and find his amazing
grace to help us in time of need.
An appropriate blessing
coming just at the right moment.
There's a guy who found it very
difficult to come into the king's
presence.
That guy is called Mephibosheth.
Tell your neighbor, Mephibosheth.
In first, uh I think it is 2 Samuel
chapter 9.
It's the story of Mephibosheth.
I want to read part of it and see how
this guy experienced coming into the
presence of the king.
It says, "David asked, is there anyone
still left of the house of Saul to whom
I can show kindness for Jonathan
Jonathan sick Jonathan sick." God was
ready. The king was ready.
Now, there was a servant of Saul's
household named Ziba.
There's someone here to appear before
David and the king.
And the king said to him, "Are you
Ziba?"
"At your service," he replied.
The king asked, "Is there no one still
alive from the house of the Saul to whom
I can show God's kindness?"
Ziba answered the king, "There is a
still a son of Jonathan.
He is lame in both feet."
"Where is he?" the king asked. Ziba
answered,
"He's at the house of Makir, son of
Amiel, in Lo-Debar.
So, King David had him brought from
Lo-Debar, from the house of Makir, son
of Amiel.
When Mephibosheth, son of Jonathan, the
son of Saul, came to David, he bowed
down to pay him honor.
And then David said, "Mephibosheth?"
"At your service," he replied.
"Don't be afraid,"
David said to him, "for I will surely
show you kindness for the sake of your
father, Jonathan.
I will restore to you all the land that
belonged to your grandfather Saul.
And you will always eat You will always
eat You will always eat
at my table."
What a promise.
Now, listen to Mephibosheth.
Mephibosheth bowed down and said, "What
is your servant
that you should notice
a dead dog
like me?"
Now, a dog which is alive is
is is is okay.
A dog that is dead is bad news.
Somebody who calls you a dog
is not very nice.
But when he calls you a dog in Kikuyu,
it is very bad.
Hello?
Now, imagine you calling yourself a dog
in Kikuyu.
And not just a dog, a dead
dog. That is exactly what Mephibosheth
is saying. Uh, he said, "I'm a dead dog.
I don't deserve it." Let me tell you
this.
The king said,
"Summon Ziba, Saul's steward, and say to
him,
'I've given your master's grandson
everything that belonged to Saul
and his family.
You and your sons and your servants are
to farm land for him and bring in the
crops so that your master's grandson may
be provided for and Mephibosheth,
grandson of your master, will always eat
at my table.
In other words,
God is saying,
when you come into the king's presence,
you have found favor.
So, rather than start excusing yourself,
saying you're a dead dog, receive the
favor and say, "Lord, I receive
everything you have for me.
I receive the favor. I know I don't
deserve it because Jonathan um
Mephibosheth didn't deserve it.
The favor was because of his father,
Jonathan.
But his grandfather had given David a a
hard time.
And so, David had every reason to kill
Mephibosheth. But because of the father,
Jonathan, and the friendships they had
together, he said, "I will bless this
boy."
The father has already decided to bless
you because of your relationship with
his son.
Hallelujah.
You have a relationship with his son,
Jesus.
And because of that relationship with
his son, Jesus, the father is saying, "I
will bless you.
I will honor you. I will favor you." You
see, that is how you can enter into
God's presence. How?
Boldly.
With confidence.
And walk in confidently, walk out
confidently. Come back
confidently, sit in his house
confidently because Mephibosheth was to
sit at the king's table all the days of
his life.
That is your portion.
So, what is your confession?
Is your confession liberating or is it a
confession that has locked you down?
You can't move. Every day you're saying
you're broke. Every day you're saying,
"I I do this." Every day you can't you
say nobody likes me. Every day you say I
don't think I will ever pass my exams.
Every day you're saying that there are
no jobs in this country. Every day
you're saying you're confessing and
locking yourself and locking yourself
and locking yourself. Today
you can liberate yourself.
Amen.
Through which confession? Number one?
Position confession. Number two?
Steadfast confession. Number three?
Bold confession.
And let me tell you this, sometimes it
takes practice.
Abraham took a long time before he could
actually believe what God had said.
And so God
is not angry at you when you one day you
doubt, another day you don't believe,
another day you confess. For some of
you, you have to untrained your
confession and train yourself for things
you've said and start training yourself
in the right direction.
What I see feel like?
I'm looking at champions.
I I'm saying I'm looking at champions.
I I I I I I I I'm looking at rich kids.
Hallelujah.
I'm looking at liberated sons and
daughters of God.
That's who you are.
And that's what you need to say again
and again even though
background
is equal different. Hello.
And I'm telling you when he does
you become unstoppable.
You become unstoppable.
Hallelujah. You become unstoppable.